#### STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

#### software developer | user experience designer

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

Tucson, Arizona stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info 520-739-8302

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python, PHP
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Handlebars
- Data visualization: Chart.js, D3.js
- Artificial intelligence: Tensorflow, Google Colab
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3
- Markup languages: HTML 5
- Server environments: Node
- Development environments: Visual Studio
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application programming interfaces: Representational state transfer (REST), WebSockets, GraphQL
- UX design: wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- **Digital media:** 3D animation, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design
- Prototyping: Figma
- eCommerce: Stripe
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG 2.1
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture

Yale University School of Art 2009 – 2011, New Haven, Connecticut

## Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) *cum laude* in Art History, Theory & Criticism

Maryland Institute College of Art 2005 – 2008, Baltimore, Maryland

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An award-winning software developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience developing software solutions to challenging problems. Passionate about crafting digital experiences users enjoy. Experienced in working with stakeholders and across teams to produce critically-acclaimed projects that deliver great value for organizations and communities.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

### Founding Director, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Art in Tech Services Inc

April 2021 – present, Tucson, Arizona (relocated from Minneapolis, MN)

- Helped clients plan and achieve project goals, meeting or exceeding client expectations.
- Designed, developed, deployed and maintained the company's website including client and administrator portals, streamlining client collaboration.
- Developed custom and original software using state-of-the-art technologies like SvelteKit and Next.js to improve performance.
- Used art in UX design and in the development of creative software solutions to improve human experiences of technology.

### Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Public Arts Commission

April 2017 – present, Tucson, Arizona (relocated from Minneapolis, MN)

- Leads a non-profit, 501(c)(4) organization that uses original software to create an art community civic engagement platform.
- Designed, developed, deployed and maintained software programs including a campaign application management system, an endorsement management system and a publicly searchable database of all the organization's endorsements.
- Developing a voter networking and organizing portal.
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art experts.
- Grew Board of Directors by 233% to include leading voices in the art community by delivering strong leadership.

#### **UX Design Consultant (contract)**

**Turnberry Solutions** 

February - May 2022, Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Worked across a UX design and software development team to produce designs for the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP) used by millions of former and current active duty military and their spouses.
- Client: FedPoint

#### Web Developer and UX Designer / Co-Founding Editor

∞ mile (Infinite Mile LLC)

July 2013 - January 2017, Detroit, Michigan

#### **WEBSITES CREATED**

- 2021 present
   Art in Tech Services Inc
   www.artintechservices.com
- 2017 present
   Public Arts Commission
   www.publicartscommission.org
- 2023

Suzanne Conti Quilts https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app

- 2022
  - JoyFoodly www.joyfoodly.com
- 2021 present web work portfolio www.stephendewyerwebwork.com
- 2013 2017

   ∞ mile (Infinite Mile)

   www.infinitemiledetroit.com

#### AWARDS AND GRANTS

## Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ *mile*

John S. and James L. Knight Foundation 2014 – 2016

# Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ *mile*Awesome Foundation 2014

- Designed, developed, deployed and maintained website featuring an online store for print anthologies and merchandise, generating thousands of dollars in revenue.
- Directed three editing staff and 78 contributors to publish 94 essays and interviews, 51 artist projects, 26 reviews and 27 works of fiction or poetry
- Wrote successful grant applications.
- Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences.

#### **COURSES**

## Certificates in Software Development, Machine Learning, UX Design and Web Accessibility

Udemy 2021 – 2024

- Beginning C++ Programming From Beginner to Beyond
- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: Al, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

#### Certificates in Software Development and Leadership University of Michigan – Coursera 2020 – 2021

- · JavaScript, jQuery, and JSON
- · Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP
- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL
- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody
- Inspiring and Motivating Individuals

#### Certificates in UX Design

Interaction Design Foundation 2020

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- Become a UX Designer from Scratch
- Human-Computer Interaction